leviton.com 2019-06-24

# Leviton Privacy Policy

_Updated May 2018_

Note on translation: This Privacy Policy Statement may have been translated into various languages for the convenience of End Users. While the translation is correct to the best of Leviton’s knowledge, Leviton is not responsible or liable in the event of an inaccuracy. English is the controlling language of this Privacy Policy Statement, and any translation has been prepared for you as a courtesy only. In the event of a conflict between the English-language version of this Privacy Policy Statement and a version that has been translated into another language, the English-language version shall control.

**1\. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT AND ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS**

Leviton is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement sets forth our current privacy practices with regard to the information we collect when you or your computer interact with our Website ([http://www.leviton.com](http://www.leviton.com/)). By accessing our Website, you acknowledge and fully understand the Privacy Statement and freely consent to the information collection and use practices described in this Website Privacy Policy Statement.

**2\. PARTICIPATING MERCHANT AND THIRD-PARTY VENDOR POLICIES**

Related services and offerings with links from this website, including vendor sites, have their own privacy statements that can be viewed by clicking on the corresponding links within each respective website. Online merchants and others who participate in the services offered on our Website are encouraged to participate in industry privacy initiatives and to take a responsible attitude towards consumer privacy. However, since we do not have direct control over the policies or practices of participating merchants and other third parties, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those sites. We recommend and encourage that you always review the privacy policies of merchants and other third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties.

**3\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

When you use or connect to the Leviton website through your computer or a mobile device, Leviton collects certain information from and about its users in a few ways: directly from our web server logs, from the User, with the aid of cookies, with web beacons, and through the use of website analytics through a third party service provider. The type of information that gets collected depends on the section of our site that the user accesses. A large portion of our website can be accessed by the general public without a need to share any kind of personal information. In those areas of the site, the information collected may include IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, session length, etc. This information, of anonymous nature, allows Leviton to measure the performance of its website, and come up with possible improvements for it. Leviton may use this type information, which does not reveal the user identity, in whatever fashion it deems necessary.

Visitors to our website can register to create an account, access the website, and download Software. When you register for an account, we will request some personal information such as your name, address, e-mail, telephone number or fax number, location, and other relevant information. Leviton will not resell, or share this information with any outside entity unless that’s required in order for us to comply with a law, or a court order, or to protect our vital business interests.

When you purchase products from the Leviton website, your complete purchase order is processed by Leviton, but your payment information is submitted directly by you to a third party website for processing of your payment only. Leviton does not collect, store, or see your credit card information.

Leviton is committed to protecting your personal information from unauthorized access by having various administrative and technology safeguards in place. Any page at our site that asks you for sensitive information is highly secure. Most browsers will show a lock icon in the bottom status bar on secure pages. Look for this icon on any web page that asks for sensitive information.

Any other communication you transmit to the website, such as questions, comments, suggestions, or the like, will not be encrypted or otherwise secured or treated confidentially.

**Web Server Logs**  
When you visit our Website, we may track information through web server logs to better administer the site and analyze its usage. Examples of information we may track include but is not limited to your Internet Protocol address, the type of browser or computer you use, the number of links you click within the Website, the geographical location from which you accessed it, the date and time of your visit, the name of your Internet service provider, any web pages you linked to our Website from, and pages you viewed on the Website.

**Use of Cookies**  
Leviton may use cookies to personalize or enhance your user experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server to identify that specific user the next time he or she visits the website. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. Hence, this simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation by providing and saving your preferences and login information, as well as providing personalized functionality.

We do not allow other companies to place cookies on our website unless there is a temporary, overriding customer value (such as integrating another site that relies on third-party cookies into the existing website).

**Modifying cookie settings**  
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. The help function of your browser should contain instructions to set your computer to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or to not receive cookies at any time. If you set your computer to not receive cookies at any time, certain personalized services cannot be provided to you, and accordingly, you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the Website features (i.e. you will be able to browse the site, but will not be able to make a purchase).

**Use of Web Beacons or GIF Files**  
This website may contain electronic images known as “Web Beacons” (also called single-pixel gifs) that allow Leviton to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Leviton may include Web Beacons in promotional e-mail messages or newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. Leviton prohibits Web Beacons from being used to collect or access your personal information.

**4\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Leviton does not track its customers over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our App that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [privacy@leviton.com](mailto:privacy@leviton.com) or write us at: 201 N. Service Road, Melville, NY 11747.

**5\. NOTICE ON DISCLOSURE OF USER PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Leviton reserves the right to share aggregated site statistics with its affiliates and strategic partners to help enhance its service offerings, but does not sell identifiable personal information to third party marketing companies. Personal User information collected by or submitted to Leviton shall not be disclosed to any third parties without your permission, unless such information: (i) is to fulfill your service requests; (ii) is required to be disclosed by law, regulation, legal process, or law enforcement or government regulatory authorities, in which case we shall give you as much advance notice as is reasonably practicable in order to allow you to limit or restrict to such disclosure; or (iii) is required to be disclosed in order for us to protect our legal rights or defend against liability; or (iv) in connection with a company reorganization, merger, acquisition, or sale.

**6\. OPTING OUT**

If you wish, you may choose not to receive emails, newsletters or other communications from the Website by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link in the email communication sent to your registered email account with the website.

**7\. ACCESSING AND CHANGING PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You can ensure that your personally identifiable information in your web account file is correct and up to date by contacting us at [privacy@leviton.com](mailto:privacy@leviton.com).

**8\. INTERNET BASED DATA TRANSFER**

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore by browsing this website and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this manner.

**9\. UNDER 13 POLICY**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 13 without first receiving verifiable parental consent, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

**10\. CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT**

Leviton may periodically update this Privacy Policy Statement. When we do, we will also revise the “updated” date at the top of this Privacy page. We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates.

**11\. FOR USERS RESIDING IN OR CITIZENS OF THE EU ONLY**

You have the right to request from Leviton information about your personal data processed, erasure of your personal data, and restriction of the processing of your personal data (such as direct marketing).

To make such a request, send an email to [privacy@leviton.com](mailto:privacy@leviton.com), and include “GDPR Personal Data Request”, along with the following: your first and last name, physical address, contact email, the information you are seeking (time frame, subject matter, and any other relevant details), and in what capacity you have interacted with Leviton online. ****

**12\. CONTACT US**

If you have questions regarding the security of our Website, our Privacy Statement, or our information collection and dissemination practices, please contact us at [privacy@leviton.com](mailto:privacy@leviton.com).

© 2018 Leviton Manufacturing Co., Inc. All rights reserved.
